There are two ways to start analyzing data in Tableau.
هناك طريقتان لبدء تحليل البيانات في Tableau.
You can either jump in and start exploring,
يمكنك إما القفز والبدء في الاستكشاف،
or you can ask questions of your data and attempt to answer them.
أو يمكنك طرح أسئلة عن بياناتك ومحاولة الإجابة عنها.
We'll start by asking this data set superstore.
سنبدأ بسؤال متجر مجموعة البيانات الكبير هذا.
What are our sales like over time?
كيف تكون مبيعاتنا مع مرور الوقت؟
If we simply double click sales in order date,
إذا قمنا ببساطة بالنقر المزدوج فوق المبيعات في تاريخ الطلب،
Tableau creates a timeline and we can see our sales are increasing over time.
فإن Tableau ينشئ جدولًا زمنيًا ويمكننا رؤية مبيعاتنا تتزايد بمرور الوقت.
Note that the mark type here says automatic.
لاحظ أن نوع العلامة هنا يشير تلقائيًا.
We can change this to be another mark type if we wanted to.
يمكننا تغيير هذا ليكون نوع علامة أخرى إذا أردنا ذلك.
There's a bunch of mark types available to work with.
هناك مجموعة من أنواع العلامات المتاحة للعمل بها.
One thing to note is if the mark type is automatic,
هناك أمر واحد يجب ملاحظته، وهو أنه إذا كان نوع العلامة تلقائي،
it can change as you make changes to the view.
فيمكن تغييره أثناء إجراء تغييرات على طريقة العرض.
Let's ask another question.
دعونا نطرح سؤالًا آخر.
What is the relationship between shipping costs and profit?
ما العلاقة بين تكاليف الشحن والربح؟
This time, we're given what looks like the start of a scatter plot.
هذه المرة، يتم إعطائنا ما يشبه بداية مخطط مبعثر.
However, Tableau is aggregating our data to
ومع ذلك، يقوم Tableau بتجميع بياناتنا إلى
the overall sum of shipping costs and the sum of profit, so we only have one mark.
إجمالي تكاليف الشحن ومجموع الأرباح، بحيث لا يكون لدينا علامة واحدة فقط.
We can bring in another field into the view to
يمكننا إحضار مجال آخر في طريقة العرض
change our breakdown of marks, such as category.
لتغيير تصنيف العلامات لدينا، مثل الفئة.
If we encode categories color,
إذا قمنا بتشفير لون الفئات،
we see one mark for each category.
فسنرى علامة واحدة لكل فئة.
If we bring in another field like market to shape,
إذا قمنا بإدخال حقل آخر مثل السوق إلى الشكل،
we get a mark per category per market.
فإننا نحصل على علامة لكل فئة في السوق.
The dimensions we add to the view like category and market,
إن الأبعاد التي نضيفها إلى العرض مثل الفئة والسوق،
define the number of marks that we see,
تحدد عدد العلامات التي نراها،
or the granularity in which we see the data.
أو التفاصيل التي نرى البيانات بها.
It's easy to change your mind about any variable that we encode.
من السهل تغيير رأيك حول أي متغير نقوم بتشفيره.
For example, if we want to change color from category to order priority,
على سبيل المثال، إذا أردنا تغيير اللون من فئة إلى أولوية الطلب،
we simply drag order priority into the color shelf.
فإننا ببساطة نسحب أولوية الطلب إلى رف اللون.
Now we see a mark per order priority per market.
الآن نرى علامة لكل أولوية الطلب لكل سوق.
If we want to make marks at a certain granularity but without encoding by color or shape,
إذا أردنا إنشاء علامات على مستوى معين من الدقة، ولكن بدون تشفير حسب اللون أو الشكل،
we can bring the field to the level of detail shelf.
فيمكننا إحضار الحقل إلى مستوى رف التفاصيل.
It's important to know how adding dimensions to the marks card impacts the visual.
من المهم معرفة كيفية تأثير إضافة الأبعاد إلى بطاقة العلامات على التأثير المرئي.
And the better you understand this,
وكلما فهمت ذلك بشكل أفضل،
the more precisely you can build data visualizations.
زادت دقة إنشاء مؤثرات عرض البيانات.